Guide to the John Hall Paxton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- 1944 to 1952: American Relations in Post-War China and Iran, 1944 - 1952; Series III; 4'7" (11 boxes)
  - WRITINGS
    - Memoranda
      - On Problems with Leasing Additional Office Space, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 87)
      - On the Imprisonment of Henry K. Chan, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 87)
      - Exchange of Professors & Specialists with China, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 88)
      - Political Report on Nationalist-Communist Conflict, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 88)
      - Miscellaneous memoranda, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 88)
      - Evaluation of Consulate Personnel in Tihwa, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 89)
      - Rough Drafts on Tihwa, China, 1947, undated (Box 6, Folder 90)
      - Not by Paxton:
        - On Paxton's Escape from China (Box 6, Folder 91)
        - Editorial Stands of Iranian Newspapers, 1950-1952 (Box 6, Folder 91)
        - Guidelines for Speaking Honoraria (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Other Writings
      - Press Releases & Circulars, 1946, 1950-1951, undated (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - Speech Notes & Itinerary on Paxton's Escape from China, 1949-1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 93)
      - Newpaper Clippings:
        - Escape from China & its aftermath, 1949-1951 (Box 6, Folder 94)
        - Iran, 1951, undated (Box 6, Folder 95)
      - Articles Published by Paxton:
        - Escape Over the Roof of the World (Saturday Evening Post ) (Box 6, Folder 96)
        - Flight from China (U.S. Camera ) (Box 6, Folder 96)
      - Manuscript rough draft of Consul to Sinkiang (Box 6, Folder 97)
      - Unpublished book: Consul to Sinkiang (Box 6a, Folder 97a)
      - Cultural & Language Notes on Iran, undated (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - Cultural & Language Notes on Turki Russian & Chinese, 1946, undated (Box 7, Folder 99)
      - Lease between Ma Yi-Guin & the Secretary of State drafted by Paxton, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Outgoing Correspondence
      - February 1944 - November 1946 (Box 7, Folder 101)
      - January 1947 - December 1949 (Box 7, Folder 102)
      - January - March 1950 (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - April 1950 (Box 7, Folder 104)
      - May 1950 (Box 7, Folder 105)
      - June 1950 (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - July - August 1950 (Box 7, Folder 107)
      - September - December 1950 (Box 7, Folder 108)
      - January - February 1951 (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - March - April 1951 (Box 7, Folder 110)
      - May - June 1951 (Box 7, Folder 111)
      - July - October 1951 (Box 7, Folder 112)
      - Nov 1951 - Feb 1952 (Box 8, Folder 113)
      - Mar - Jun 1952 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Incoming Correspondence
      - A - A1, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 115)
      - Am - Az, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 116)
      - Ba - Bz, 1945-1946, (1950-1952), undated (Box 8, Folder 117)
      - C-D, 1946 (1950-1952), undated (Box 8, Folder 118)
      - E - H, 1945, 1946, 1949, (1950-1952), undated (Box 8, Folder 119)
      - I - K, 1946, 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 120)
      - L, 1944, 1946, 1949 (1950), 1952, undated (Box 8, Folder 121)
      - Ma - Mal, 1945, (1950-1951), 1952 (Box 8, Folder 122)
      - Mam - Mz, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 123)
      - N - O, 1949, (1950-1951) (Box 8, Folder 124)
      - P, 1945, 1959 (1950), 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 125)
      - R, 1945, 1946, 1949, (1950-1952) (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - S - Sat, (1950)-1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - Sav - Sd, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Se - Sg, 1950-1954 (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Sh, 1949-(1950-1951)-1952 (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - Si - So, 1946, 1950-1952, undated (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - Sp - Ss, 1951-1952, undated (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - St - Sz, 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 133)
      - T, 1946, 1949, (1950-1951), 1952, undated (Box 8, Folder 134)
      - U - V, 1944, 1946 (1950-1951), 1952, undated (Box 8, Folder 135)
      - Wa - We, 1946 (1950-1952) (Box 8, Folder 136)
      - Wf - Wq, 1946, 1950-1952, undated (Box 9, Folder 137)
      - Wr - Wz, 1949-(1950)-1951 (Box 9, Folder 138)
      - X - Z, 1950-1952, undated (Box 9, Folder 139)
      - Unidentified, 1948, 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 140)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Photographs of Tihwa, Sinkiang (427 b&w; 31 color) (Box 10, Folder 141)
    - Portrait of Paxton, undated (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - 27 photos of Northwest China, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - 33 photographs of Northwestern China, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - Photo album containing photos of Paxton's escape from China, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - Photo album containing photos of Paxton's escape from China, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - Photographs of Paxton's Trip to Iran via Beirut, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 146)
- Personal, Series IV; 1'8" (7 boxes)
  Series IV contains personal material which has no direct bearing on any one phase of Paxton's diplomatic career. It also contains the correspondence and writings of Vincoe Paxton.
  Writings in this series are divided into Yale College essays, poetry, and plays, lists and inventories, writings of others, and maps. There are also several folders of miscellaneous material.
  This series also contains Paxton's financial correspondence, which is arranged chronologically. Paxton's outgoing family correspondence is arranged chronologically, and his incoming letters are arranged alphabetically by author. Vincoe Paxton's writings are arranged chronologically, as is her outgoing correspondence. Her incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - WRITINGS
    - Essays, Poetry, Exams written by Paxton at Yale, 1920, 1922, undated (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - Essays written by Paxton at Yale, 1921, undated (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - Short stories written by Paxton at Yale, [1920-1922?] (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - Plays written by Paxton at Yale, [1920-1922?]
      - The King of the Beggars (Box 16, Folder 150)
      - Yale and Hades (Box 16, Folder 150)
      - Sandalwood (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - Lists & Inventories, 1936, 1939, 1941, 1946, 1951, undated (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - Lists & Inventories of Paxton's Personal Belongings, 1939, 1946, undated (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - Radio Scripts
      - Messenger of Peace, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 153)
      - The Foreign Service in China, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - Articles & Misc. Writings of Others, 1924, 1941, (1950-1951) (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - Miscellaneous Pamphlets (Box 16, Folder 155)
    - Bibliography of the American Council of Learned Societies, Committee on Far Eastern Studies, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 156)
    - Maps
      - Middle East - Political Sub-Divisions of India - The World (Box 17, Folder 157)
      - Far East - Northern Africa - China Coast Pacific Ocean - Northern Europe - California (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Restricted Correspondence, 1940, 1935-1941, 1940-1943 (Box 17, Folder 159-161)
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Outgoing Correspondence
      - 1927 - 1928, 1937, 1943-December 1943, September 1944, 1949, March - August 1951 (Box 17, Folder 162-168)
      - Undated (Box 17, Folder 169)
    - Incoming Correspondence
      - Una Paxton, 1938, September 1941 - October 1942 (Box 17, Folder 170)
      - Una Paxton, November 1942 - April 1943 (Box 17, Folder 171)
      - Una Paxton, May 1943 - August 1943 (Box 17, Folder 172)
      - Una Paxton, September - November 1943 (Box 17, Folder 173)
      - Una Paxton, February - June 1951 (Box 17, Folder 174)
      - Ann Paxton, 1942 December 12 (Box 17, Folder 175)
      - Vincoe Paxton, 1946 March 25 (Box 17, Folder 175)
      - W.T. Paxton, undated (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    General note
    Folio
    - Passports (Box 18, Folder 176)
    - Biographical Information, Medical Reports, Records of Promotions, etc. (Box 18, Folder 177)
    - Certificates, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 178)
    - Minutes of Chefoo Harbor Improvement Commission, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 179)
    - Fifty "Soundscriber" Recording Discs (Box 18, Folder 180)
    - Watercolor by Una Paxton, 1909 (Box 18, Folder 181)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 18, Folder 182)
    - Miscellaneous Material (Box 18, Folder 183-184)
    - Paxton's Guest Book, 1929-1955 (Box 19, Folder 185)
    - Paxton's Autograph Book from the Brethren of Pearl River Lodge, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 185)
    - Certificates (3) Awarding the Position of U.S. Consul, (1942, 1951) (Box 19A, Folder 185)
    - Masonic Certificates (3), (1930, 1933) (Box 19A, Folder 185)
    - Unidentified Iranian Certificate, undated (Box 19A, Folder 185)
    - Membership Certificate in the Grand Lodge of the Philippine Island, (1937) (Box 19A, Folder 185)
  - WRITINGS OF VINCOE PAXTON
    - Published Article & Report:
      - Among Men of Asia, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 186)
      - A Plan for Nursing Education in Illinois, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 186)
  - CORRESPONDENCE OF VINCOE PAXTON
    - Outgoing Correspondence
      - March - December 1950 (Box 20, Folder 187)
      - February - June 1951, June - September 1952, January - November 1953 (Box 20, Folder 188)
      - 1954 - 1958, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 189)
    - Incoming Correspondence
      - A, 1943, 1949, 1950, 1952-1953, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 190)
      - B, 1951, 1952, 1954, undated (Box 20, Folder 191)
      - C - F, 1943, 1952, 1954-1957, undated (Box 20, Folder 192)
      - G - H, 1950, 1952-1954, 1956, undated (Box 20, Folder 193)
      - I - M, 1950, 1952-1953, 1957-1958, undated (Box 20, Folder 194)
      - N - O, 1951 - 1955 (Box 21, Folder 195)
      - P, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 196)
      - Q - S, 1950-1954, 1957, undated (Box 21, Folder 197)
      - T - U, 1952-1954, 1956-1957, undated (Box 21, Folder 198)
      - W, 1950-1953, undated (Box 21, Folder 199)
      - X - Z, 1952-1953, undated (Box 21, Folder 200)
      - Unidentified (Box 21, Folder 201)